Luis Herrera

1209@holbertonschool.com

linkedin.com/in/lh1008

https://lh1008.github.io/

Summary

Cryptocurrency privacy-focused Monero (XMR) enthusiast. Focused on open-source software GNU/Linux operating systems since 2016.

Studied Software Engineering foundations at Holberton School Colombia with a high passion for blockchain technology. Entrepreneur, adventurer, and eager to develop code for our world.

I have experience as a Support Engineer. The programming languages I feel most interests in are C and Python. I've done Python scripting, hand-coded HTML, and CSS. I understand SQL database compliance and worked on relational database management systems, like MySQL and PostgreSQL.

Experience



Support Engineer

Addi

Dec 2021 - Present (2 years 3 months)

- Client technical support: resolve CX (customer experience team) requests, workflows, user flow, and app issues, analyze technical client logs, error detection, request escalation, and training.
- Engineering Support: request escalation, detect/open incidents (analiyze impact), share logs, stats.
- Engineering projects: built automated API tool project, automation scripting.

Software: Slack, PostgreSQL, Kustomer, Mezmo (LogDNA), LogRocket, Grafana schedule handler, incidents, and log analyzer), Databricks (automated cluster management; graphical command-line interface), Sublime (IDE), Python, PostgreSQL, Notion (documentation), Asana (task management), Lucidchart (diagrams).

Development: SCRUM (sprints)

Software Engineer

Blockchain Labb

Sep 2020 - Sep 2021 (1 year 1 month)

- Development Coordinator: organize and coordinate development working directly with the developers to follow the company's needs and blockchain integrations.
- Code Reviewer: check the developer's code and make the tryouts.
- Repository and Server Maintainer: maintain, review, and check repository's commits and accept changes. SysOps/DevOps server maintainer.
- Programming Languages: Vuejs, Nuxtjs, Nodejs.

Communication Work-group Coordinator

Monero

Jul 2018 - Present (5 years 8 months)

- Workgroup communication coordinator
- Project task management coordinator
- Junior SysOps/DevOps maintainer

Database Analyst

EMCALI - Telecomunicaciones

Sep 2016 - Feb 2018 (1 year 6 months)

- Database Analyst: Microsoft Excel
- GIS (Geographic Information System) Analyst: GEOVISOR/MapInfo software
- Recruiter: assistant training
- Software: OPEN-SmartFlex utility software

Business Development Administrator

Productos Vrinda

Feb 2013 - May 2016 (3 years 4 months)

- Production manager and service representative
- Sales

Education

Holberton School

Software Engineer, Programming

2019 - 2021

Foundations - Full Stack Developer

- Programming Languages: C, Python, Javascript.
- Web Stack Development: HTML, CSS, Nginx, HaProxy.
- Database Management: MySQL.
- Application, programs, software: Git, Github, Docker.

Specialization - Low Level & Algorithms

- Programming Languages: C, Python, Assembly (libASM).

Udemy Academy

Web Designer, Web Development

2017 - 2018

Web Development Languages: HTML, CSS.

Licenses & Certifications

Python Data Structures - University of Michigan GYVVPA3N7JXL

Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python) - University of Michigan Z9J35QEGB8JY

- **EF SET Certificate** EF Standard English Test (EF SET)
 C1 ADVANCED
- **EF SET English Certificate 94/100 (C1 Advanced)** EF Standard English Test (EF SET)

Skills

English • Open Source Software • Software Development • Business Strategy • Project Management
 MySQL • C (Programming Language) • Python (Programming Language) • PostgreSQL